The world is full of coincidences.
Twenty-five years ago,
I had a fateful encounter with Mariko.
I've always just watched over here.
But now, she is finally aware of me.
Coincidences can be manufactured.
A coincidence meant to make Mariko smile.
However,
there are plenty of people who approach
Mariko and those who envy her.
They say Mr. Tateiwa was killed.
I must do what I need to.
Who is this man…
Because I'm the one by Mariko's side…
protecting her.
Excuse me.
May I speak with you for a moment?
INSPECTOR TAISUKE SAKURA
Yes.
Where were you
on July 7, around 10:25 p.m.?
Is that when the thing
with Mr. Tateiwa happened?
Yes.
Was I caught on a security camera?
That's probably what
the police have gathered.
So, what?
I was meeting with Tateiwa at the place
on the news where the incident happened.
What were you doing there?
We were talking about work.
In a place like that,
outside of working hours?
Yes, that is correct.
Immediately after meeting with you,
Tateiwa was murdered by someone.
I am shocked.
Normally, you wouldn't have
any contact with the victim, Mr. Tateiwa,
who is a director, right?
-What specifically were you talking about?
-Uh…
It wasn't on camera, was it?
The part where I killed Tateiwa.
Since it wasn't on camera,
that means I didn't do it.
TOKYO POLICE TAISUKE SAKURA
INSPECTOR
THANKS FOR WATCHING THE DRAMA
"BACK TO SQUARE ONE, DETECTIVE"
PUBLIC ORDER MAINTENANCE
TAISUKE SAKURA
AWARD
MERITORIOUS SERVICE AWARD
TAISUKE SAKURA
There are things I must do.
-I'm first!
-I'm second.
It's cold!
Can you reach out your hand?
It's okay.
It's not scary if we hold hands.
Let's go.
Ready, and…
The cold water feels great.
I've seen it before.
I've seen Mariko's smile before.
Oh.
But that was different.
What was?
The power of it.
Thank you.
She…
smiled at me…
At me…
So you're saying that peeking at a smile
meant for someone else
is different in impact compared
to a smile directed at you?
It was so cute.
Oh, no, not like that.
I'm not talking
about her looks or anything.
I get it, I get it.
I understand.
You want to be the only one
who can make her smile
and the only one who gets to see it.
And you'll start wanting more things
that are just for you.
People call that possessiveness.
Well, it's a natural part of love.
-What, for you too?
-No, not me.
I've never been that obsessed
with a single person.
But it's like that for you, right?
I'm sure that soon, you'll start hating it
when she smiles at other people.
Be careful.
No way that will happen.
I want Mariko's life to be happy.
So,
I want her to always be smiling,
no matter who she's with.
But…
NOSE COSMETICS
Lately, Mariko is far from smiling.
She's in an extremely bad mood.
Why?
Because her birthday is approaching.
More precisely, the annual
family birthday celebration
at her parents' house is approaching.
Here you go.
Thank you.
-You really don't have to do this.
-No, I was making one anyway.
-Izumi.
-Yes?
Will you come to my family's house
with me the day after tomorrow?
There's no way I can go.
I…
don't like her.
The president's wife, I mean.
Not that I dislike the president, though.
He's a good person. Kind too.
Who knows? I don't know him well.
There you go again.
Maybe it's just that you don't
open up enough, Mariko?
If you showed your true feelings more,
wouldn't you get closer?
If you could open up to someone,
it would ease your mind more too, Mariko.
Really?
Yes.
Well, I'm actually not good
at sharing things with people.
What? Really?
Any progress on the project?
Speak of the devil…
-I will check on it.
-Thank you.
Outside of work,
Mariko and the president
have almost no communication.
I've watched many types
of parents and children, but…
I heard Hatano was released
from prison, right?
Be careful.
It was a long time ago, but he might talk
about things involving you too.
GINJIRO NOSE
YEAR 6, CLASS 3
NO. 1 GOLD STAR CLASS
SATORU HATANO
GINJIRO NOSE
Is the issue the father as an individual?
Or is it the whole family
as a collective unit?
I want Mariko to smile.
So,
I must eliminate the risk factors
that stand in the way.
I'm home, Mom.
Mariko?
Hi, I'm back.
Welcome home.
Your father is out for a bit right now,
but we'll start as soon as he returns.
Yes, hello?
Sorry, I know it's your day off.
I didn't know you were
at your parents' before I called.
I should have waited
until the beginning of the week.
It'll cause trouble
for their side if it's late.
-Wait here a second.
-Okay.
Oh, can I help you?
Chairwoman! I am Yukimura
from the Brand Business Department.
I forgot to have the samples
confirmed yesterday.
Oh, well, thank you. Anyway, come in.
Oh, no, no.
I'll be leaving soon. I'll just wait here.
No, it's okay.
In the old days, all the employees
would often come over to eat.
Come on, quickly!
I definitely prefer
The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle too.
Right!
Well, Norwegian Wood is good too,
but this is definitely
his true masterpiece.
Mariko's grandmother
likes Haruki Murakami.
On the release day of a new book…
…she is a die-hard fan
who queues at bookstores
for hours before they open to get a copy.
It is said that in that work,
the expression of evil,
which had been fantastical until then,
began to take shape as real evil
accompanied by history and physicality.
Yes, exactly!
Oh, have you read the new one?
No, not yet.
I'll lend it to you then.
-What, really?
-Yes.
Wow, thank you so much.
-Here.
-Yes.
Thank you very much.
Well, I'll be going now.
Already? Stay for lunch.
Mom, that's too short notice for him.
Do you have plans after this?
No, well, I don't, but…
Eat with us, why not?
What?
You can just email this
after work today, right?
But…
Man, I'm starving.
Who are you?
Come, sit here.
Ah, excuse me.
I'm home.
-Welcome back.
-Welcome home.
President…
Thank you for the other day.
Oh, Yukimura. Hello.
Welcome home.
I'll go wash my hands.
Mariko, have this too. You like it, right?
Thank you very much.
Mariko's stepmother, Sayuri,
came into the family
when Mariko was seven years old.
THERE'S A NEW LADY THERE NOW
She entered the family less than a year
after Mariko's mother passed away.
THANK YOU FOR THE 25 YEARS
#MARRIAGEANNIVERSARY
With Mariko being so outstanding,
our company is in safe hands.
It's not your company.
She is clearly
someone who's just after money.
No, it's normal for obvious things
to have especially complex layers to them.
We must not let our guard down.
You're making a show
of cooking Kyoko's specialty dish.
You have a lot of nerve, honestly.
Oh, come now, Mother.
This is a recipe I taught Kyoko.
I made it with Kyoko and Mariko
when she was a kid, right?
This is the first I've heard of it.
This woman and Mariko's mother
were old acquaintances.
Mariko, when Keito joins
the company next year,
take care of him, okay?
What? No way.
I'm not working under her.
Isn't my sister scary?
Well, no, she isn't.
More importantly, Keito,
are you sure you're going
to graduate from univeristy?
Well, it'll work out somehow.
-It won't work out if you don't work hard.
-My alarm
-isn't triggered by you for now.
-All right, all right,
I'll do my best.
Keito, I sense that Mariko
actually cares for you in her own way.
So he's the problem after all.
Yukimura.
Yes.
Mariko has strong preferences,
so she isn't causing trouble for everyone
in the Brand Business Department, is she?
Not at all.
Everyone is motivated and working hard.
-Is that so?
-Yes.
So this is the young employee
you played golf with
the other day.
Yukimura is very good at golf.
He's also polite.
Let's go again soon.
I would be honored.
When did you join Mariko's department?
I didn't know at all.
It's only been about two weeks.
Since Mariko selected you,
you must be very capable, huh?
Mariko doesn't speak much,
so you sometimes find it difficult
to know what she's thinking, right?
No, it's not a problem.
She has been cool since she was a child,
and she almost never
complains or acts spoiled.
As her father, I often don't know
what she's thinking either.
Give Mariko your support.
Oh, well, it would be my honor.
You don't need to say all of that.
-We're back.
-Hello.
That Sota Yukimura guy you're hounding
doesn't have much
of a presence at his company.
Nobody knows much about him.
All we know is he was transferred
to the Brand Department recently.
-Transferred?
-Well,
the president's daughter
selected him specially.
It's unprecedented.
The president's daughter…
The president's daughter
is Mariko Nose, right?
Oh, well,
there is witness information
that the victim, Tateiwa,
and Mariko Nose
were arguing in the company
on the day of the incident.
Does it mean those two
being in the same department
has some connection?
SOTA YUKIMURA
You seem like you like sweets.
-I do.
-I'm glad.
I'm going to freshen up.
-Straight out, second door on the right.
-Okay.
You brought someone home to us, huh?
First time ever.
He just came without asking.
I'm sorry for forcing you
to come with me today.
Not at all.
I enjoyed it.
Liar.
You actually hated it, didn't you?
I didn't hate it,
I was just quite nervous.
Of course you were.
I'm sorry.
But you fit in surprisingly well.
Me?
I was really out of place.
No, you fit in better than me.
You are a mysterious person.
Like someone who always
has perfect timing.
You give me what I want, when I want it.
You appear at the perfect time.
Really?
Yes.
Like a wall.
I just notice that you're there.
But whether you're actually there or not
doesn't really bother me.
Sorry.
Does "sorry" mean that was an insult?
No, that's not what I meant at all.
Is the birthday party an annual tradition?
Yes.
It's easy to just refuse to go, but…
Actually…
when I was a kid, I hated it so much
that I ran away from home.
But today,
I've decided to definitely go home
because I want to celebrate my mother.
Your mother?
Yes.
A birthday is the day a mother worked hard
to give birth to her child, right?
If anything, that is more precious.
So, the gathering earlier
was a celebration for my mother.
You really are kind, Mariko.
What, how?
I just want to put pressure on my father.
To show him that I won't forgive him
if he forgets my mother.
It's a spiteful way of thinking.
My dad probably thinks
it's annoying deep down too.
I don't think so.
Because every year, only on this day,
he comes home without scheduling any work.
He just really wants
to celebrate your birthday.
How do you know something like that?
Ah…
I just thought that must be the case.
Wait a second.
Thank you for waiting.
-Thank you.
-Thank you very much.
Um…
Here.
I didn't get you a birthday present, so…
-I'm sorry. I've overstepped.
-Oh, no.
Thank you.
Is the gathering
the only thing you do to celebrate?
Yes.
In the first place, I hate birthdays.
I'm not good with events and things.
I see.
Today is Mariko's birthday.
I also attended the annual birthday party
held at her family's house
this year.
Ever since that year,
Mariko's always hated her birthday.
So this is your spot, huh?
Yes. I've been coming a lot lately.
Wow…
Oh, Mariko, welcome.
-Oh…
Hello.
Mariko and Yukimura
went to the same university?
Yes, it feels like
a fateful reunion, doesn't it?
Well, I don't know about fate.
How long have you been running this shop?
Since last autumn. Almost a year now.
Wow, I didn't notice it at all.
You've been coming
since I first opened, right, Mariko?
I suppose so.
What?
Does that mean you knew Mariko
all this time, but never spoke to her?
-Isn't that creepy?
-What? That'd be scary.
I was being considerate.
But Mariko didn't know, right?
To be known one-sidedly…
Wouldn't you want him
to just speak to you already?
No, um, I was glad he left me alone.
If he had spoken to me,
I probably would have stopped coming.
No way, what? But it's okay now, right?
Yes, it's fine.
Oh, thank goodness. That startled me.
I thought Sota would get mad at me.
What? Yukimura?
Oh, no, uh, just talking to myself, yes.
-Excuse me.
-Oh, yes? I'm coming.
Well then, enjoy.
-One person, right?
-Yes.
He's Yukimura's friend, right?
-They're pretty different…
-Yes.
But he doesn't seem like a bad person.
That's true.
Manager.
Please take a look at this.
Just leave those. I'll check later.
Izumi, um…
What is it?
Did you have a fight?
No.
It's not that. It's just that
the Keihin Department Store samples…
This is bad! Mariko!
-Its really bad!
-What's wrong?
Yukimura is suspected in Tateiwa's case.
What?
It seems the police
are questioning our employees.
Several people said
they were asked about Yukimura.
-Sorry for doing this during work hours.
-No.
I haven't taken my lunch break yet.
It's perfect timing.
Have a seat.
Since I didn't hear from you,
I thought I might have been rejected.
I'm sorry. I've been very busy
with some things.
Your work seems busy.
There is one thing I wanted to ask.
Yes, ask me anything.
Is it true that an employee of ours
is suspected in Tateiwa's case?
Man, so that's what this is about…
The reason you agreed to have a meal
with me is because I'm a police officer.
Oh, no, um…
I'm sorry.
You are a straightforward person.
Since it's under investigation,
I can't speak in detail,
but we are looking
at various possibilities.
I am truly sorry about Tateiwa.
But it is impossible
that the culprit is my subordinate.
I didn't mention this,
but I was having a dispute
with Mr. Tateiwa over work,
and we had an argument
right before the incident.
Isn't it because of that
my subordinates are suspected?
Or do the police think my subordinates
also had a bad relationship with Tateiwa?
It was my personal issue.
My subordinates have nothing
to do with it.
We just need to investigate
from all angles,
so please don't worry.
Of course. I'm sorry.
You are a good boss, Mariko.
To be so desperate
to protect your subordinates…
It's just as your grandmother said.
Mariko isn't very sociable,
but she is a kind child.
She told me that many times before we met.
She said that?
You're a lot like your mother.
She was a quiet person,
but she was like a sunflower
blooming in the family.
You're exactly like her.
My grandmother told you all that?
You might have heard,
but my mother died
in an accident when I was seven.
That must have been very sad for you.
I'm not sure what to say…
Oh, no, it's okay.
I'm a full adult now.
It's something from the past.
How about finding a new place?
Instead of the past, creating a new future
might be better for you.
That was weird, wasn't it…
-Oh, no…
-I'm sorry.
I want Mariko to smile.
If that smile were to belong
to someone else…
NEW ASSETS
HELLO, THIS IS KIKUTA.
I SHOULD BE ABLE TO REPORT BACK
ON THE MATTER YOU REQUESTED TOMORROW.
KIKUTA PRIVATE INVESTIGATION
What?
A detective agency?
Good work, everyone. I'm heading out.
-Goodbye.
-Thank you.
FATHER
Yes?
Understood.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Sorry, this isn't about work.
What is it?
Sayuri asked me to give this to you.
This is Mom's…
She had it repaired to fit your size.
Contact her and thank her.
I didn't ask for this…
I didn't ask for this!
Why would she do this without asking?
Why is she touching Mom's things
without permission?
Sayuri was only thinking of you--
I'm saying that it's selfish!
Mariko.
Ah, manager.
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday, Mariko.
This is wrong.
This is all wrong!
Mariko!
Mom…
Mariko…
Why?
I felt like you were crying.
What?
What are you saying?
Wait, how did you know I was here?
I just happened to be passing by.
You just happened to?
You're completely out of breath.
What are you?
Giving me the flower my mother liked
and even knowing this park…
This is a special place, isn't it?
This is…
my sanctuary.
When I was a kid,
whenever something bad happened,
I always came here.
Because when I was here,
Mom would come to get me.
The year my mother died…
I ran away from home
because I hated the birthday party.
Alone.
Even though I knew Mom
wouldn't come to get me anymore.
But strangely…
being here made me feel
like Mom was nearby,
and I was able
to return home safely
without losing my way.
Wait…
Why am I telling you this?
You hate birthdays
because they remind you of your mother.
You hate the birthday parties
because you loved the birthday parties
your mother threw for you.
My father is right.
I'm acting like a fool at my age.
I shouldn't even worry about it.
That doesn't matter.
No matter how old you get…
or how many years pass…
you cannot forget sad things.
You just get better…
at pretending to forget,
better at lying that you forgot.
I don't think you need to force yourself
to share your true feelings
or show your weakness to anyone.
I think there are people
who are not good at that.
But…
please just at least
don't lie to yourself.
The sadness…
of losing your mother…
the loneliness…
Even the happiness of the birthday parties
she threw for you when you were a child…
Please don't seal them away
and pretend they didn't exist.
Please, keep them with you, always.
I've never cried
in front of someone before.
I'm a wall. It's okay.
I'm just here.
So don't worry.
What is that?
This is strange.
I thought I only wanted
to see Mariko smile, but…
Mom…
That white one…
The white cylindrical one
that's big at the top.
Is it this one?
No, not that. It's about this big…
Mom?
"I HELD A GRUDGE AGAINST THE ENTIRE WORLD"
It's a good article.
I hear it's selling pretty well.
But they paid me almost nothing.
This is you?
It's a tough world, huh?
I wonder if I have any other stories
that would sell for more.
A single factor
that exerts power is strong.
-But…
-…you like sweets.
-I do.
-I'm glad.
I'm going to freshen up.
-Straight out, second door on the right.
-Okay.
What time are you coming home?
Keito?
Hey, Keito!
When multiple factors intertwine,
it becomes complex and troublesome.
No.
Because I don't want
my daughter to hear about it.
Yes.
Talking again after getting out of prison,
he really is a plague.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
AWARD
Whoa…
There is still something in this family.
Something that steals Mariko's smile.
PRESIDENT'S OFFICE
Is the risk factor an individual?
-Or is it…
-Yukimura.
I need to talk to you.
I want Mariko to be happy.
That's all.
What are you to Mariko?
‎NEXT TIME…
Subtitle translation by: Maslin Friedman